<?xml version="1.0"?>

<book>
<page type="intro">
<text>Вооружение инженера
Переносит боль на новый уровень

Автор: Sheriff Bownana</text>
</page>

<page type="contents">
<text>Содержание</text>
<link>
 <text>Introduction</text>
 <icon>weaponrybook</icon>
 <jump>3</jump>
</link>
<link>
 <text>Метательное оружие</text>
 <icon>throwingknifeIcon</icon>
 <jump>5</jump>
</link>
<link>
 <text>Оружие дальнего боя</text>
 <icon>shortbowIcon</icon>
 <jump>7</jump>
</link>
<link>
 <text>Снаряды</text>
 <icon>arrowIcon</icon>
 <jump>10</jump>
</link>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>Почему нужно подойти, чтобы ударить, когда можно сделать это, стоя здесь!

Инженер знает как делать разное оружие дальнего боя. Существует две большие категории: метательное оружие и оружие, которое выстреливает снаряды.

Оба типа используют систему боеприпасов. Оружие дальнего боя состоит из одного предмета, который состоит из многих других. Зачем нужно нести 2 стака стрел, когда можно нести 200 стрел в одном стаке!
У этих предметов нету прочности, но они тратятся за каждое метание/выстрел.</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>Метательное оружие:
* Метательный нож
* Сюрикэн
* Копьё

Оружие дальнего боя:
* Короткий лук
* Длинный лук
* Арбалет

Снаряды:
* Стрелы
* Болты</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>Метательное оружие

Метательные ножи:
Эти ножи создаются из лезвия ножа и ручки.
Удерживайте ПКМ, чтобы прицелиться, отпустите ПКМ, чтобы кинуть нож.
Количество метательных ножей - умеренное, также они наносят умеренный урон.

Сюрикэн:
Маленькие тонкие снаряды, собранные из 4 частей, которые бросают от запястья. Благодаря этому Вам не нужно целиться и Вы можете кидать их сразу.
Они настолько малы, что Вы можете взять целую кучу, однако, они наносят мало урона.</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>

Копьё:
Это гибрид оружия ближнего и дальнего боя, состоящий из наконечника стрелы и двух прочных стержней. В ближнем бою оно наносит умеренный урон, чтобы высвободить его истинную силу, Вам нужно кинуть его во врага.
Бросок занимает кое-какое время. Из-за их размера, Вы можете нести лишь несколько штук.</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>Оружие дальнего боя

Короткий лук:
Put together from two bow limbs and a bowstring, this weapon is a fast and handy bow. Keep in mind that inflexible materials like stone can hardly be drawn back and can't accelerate projectiles well. Organic materials are favoured for quick bows, while metals require lots of strengt to draw back, but provide more power.
The bow requires arrows as ammo.
Offensive modifiers on bows do not count for arrows. The only modifiers affecting its ranged performance are Redstone and lapis.</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>

Длинный лук:
The big brother. This bow is much bigger, requiring more time to pull it back, but boy oh boy are those arrows fast.
Because of this the longbow performs slightly better against armored targets. Furthermore this makes the longbow less accurate with very light arrows.
The longbow is constructed from two bow limbs, a bowstring and a large plate.</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>

Арбалет:
Those pesky metals are such a pain to pull back. Luckily a tinkerer knows how to help himself! The crossbow allows you to pre-load it with a bolt, and have it ready instantly to fire. Since this allows for much more power, it can shoot heavier projectiles, resulting in more damage and armor penetration.
To load a crossbow simply rightclick and wait until the animation is done. The loading process can be stopped by pressing rightclick while sneaking. The crossbow can be unloaded in the same way.</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>Снаряды
For these projectiles goes: The heavier the projectile, the more damage carries through armor.

Стрелы:
The bread and butter of every ranger. Arrows can be built from many different materials. It needs an arrow head, a shaft and a fletching.
The choice of materials allows a balance between damage, arrow-count, accuracy and fragility. The head material is crucial for its weight.
A fragile arrow has a chance to break on impact with terrain. Arrows always break when they hit a target, however the reinforced trait gives a chance for the arrow to survive the impact.</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>

Доступные материалы для стержня:
* Палка
* Сахарный тростник
* Кость
* Огненный стержень

Доступные материалы для оперения:
* Листва
* Слизистая листва
* Перья
* Слизь</text>
</page>

<page type="text">
<text>

Болты:
Crafting bolts is a delicate process. First you need a core in the form of a tool rod.
Take this tool rod to a smeltery and put it into a Casting Table. Pour some metal onto it to coat the tip with a more damaging material.
After this process, add a fletching and your bolts are ready to be used.

Since the bolts consist of a harder core and tip they carry more weight than regular arrows, making them perfect to fight armored targets.</text>
</page>

</book>
